SHAHEEN AHAMMED K

WEB DEVELOPER CUM GRAPHIC DESIGNER

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaheen-ahammed/ | https://shaheenahmd.netlify.app/https://www.behance.net/shaheenahmd | https://github.com/shaheenahmd





SUMMARY

Dedicated and skilled Web Developer with 3 years of experience on implementing innovative web designs and user experiences. Seeking a challenging position in a reputed organization to contribute my technical skills and creativity to achieve personal and organizational goals.

EDUCATION

Python Full stack Developer Internship Program | Calicut, Kerala, India 2020 - 2021

Bachelor Of Science In Mathematics With Computer Science | University Of Calicut, Kerala, India - 2019

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS

Frameworks/Libraries : React, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, jQuery **Familiar with :** Python, Django, MySQL, PHP, Restful APIs

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Responsive Design: Media queries, Flex-box, Grid

Others: WordPress, SEO

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator, Figma

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Quick learning, Leadership, Team Collaboration, Time Management, Flexibility

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCER | WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Dec 2023 - Present | Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Managing E- commerce platform of company who selling electronics products.
- Designed visually appealing graphics and marketing materials for digital medias.
- Developed and maintained responsive websites for various clients, ensuring optimal user experience.
- Collaborated with clients to understand their business goals and translate them into functional and visually appealing websites.

FREELANCER | WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Jun 2023 - November | Kerala, India

- Implemented responsive websites that provide optimal user experiences across all devices and screen sizes, ensuring accessibility and functionality.
- Provided graphic design services to clients, creating visually appealing and effective designs for various projects and social media ads.

PENTACODES LLP | JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

March 2023 - May 2023 | Kochi, Kerala

- Developed and maintained websites using modern technologies, ensuring high performance and compatibility across various devices.
- Participated in the optimization of website speed and performance, resulting in a decrease in page load times.
- Debugged and resolved front-end issues to ensure smooth website performance.

EXIMUZ TECHNOLABS | JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

September 2021 - February 2023 | Calicut, Kerala

- Assisted in the creation of visually appealing and intuitive websites by translating UI/UX designs into code.
- Developed and maintained user-friendly and responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and React.

• Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers and back-end developers to implement efficient and visually appealing user interfaces.

PROJECTS WORKED

Business / Informative Websites, Landing Pages | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery Python, and PHP.

- Clearly define the purpose of the website and align it with the business goals.
- Developed a mobile-first approach with media queries for optimal viewing on various devices.
- Implemented SEO best practices such as meta tags, keyword optimization, and sitemap submission to enhance the website's visibility on search engines.

E- Commerce Website | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery and PHP

- Implemented all the necessary E- commerce functionalities like product listing, cart, orders Wish list etc.
- Employed to create a responsive and flexible layout, enhancing the website's accessibility and usability.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and optimized performance for faster load times.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Weather Application | React.js, OpenWeatherMap API

Integrated with API to dynamically fetch and update weather information. - Live Link

Movie Trailer App | React.js, TMDB API

The movie trailer App provide details of trending movies, API integration of TMDB. - Live Link

Hospital Management Website | Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Developed dynamic website, here user can get all information about the hospital. - Github Link

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent) | Malayalam (Fluent) | Hindi (Intermediate level) | Arabic (Read and Write)

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

SHAHEEN AHAMMED